Inventory of the Frederick H. Chatfield papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Frederick H. Chatfield papers
1914-1919
53008
Hoover Institution Archives
2 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder, 2 envelopes, 1 framed certificate (3.1 linear feet)
Photographs, printed matter and memorabilia, relating to relief activities of the Commission for Relief in Belgium during World War I.
Chatfield, Frederick H.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1953.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Frederick H. Chatfield was a member of the Commission for Relief in Belgium (CRB). Chatfield served as secetary of the Cincinnati branch and was the CRB delegate for the Commission du Lait of Le Comité de Secours et d'Alimentation de l’Arrondissement de Liège, a relief committee trying to provide food and establish dairy production centers in Liège during World War I.
Related Collection(s)
Commission for Relief in Belgium Records, 1914-1930, Hoover Institution Archives
Scope and Content of Collection
Photographs, lithographs, printed matter, and memorabilia, relating to relief activities of the Commission for Relief in Belgium and Comité de Secours et d'Alimentation de l’Arrondissement de Liège during World War I. The collection is arranged by medium into three series: Photographs, Printed materials, and Memorabilia.
Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930)--Pictorial works.; International relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Belgium.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.
- Photographs, 1915-1917
  Scope and Contents note
  Photographs include members of the Commission for Relief in Belgium and Comité de secours et d'Alimentation de l’Arrondissement de Liège.
  - Arrowsmith, Robert, 1916 (Envelope mA)
  - Count van Hague, undated (Envelope mA)
  - C.R.B office in Liège, R. Arrowsmith and others, undated (Envelope mA)
  - Le Comité de Secours et d’Alimentation de la Province de Liège, June 1916 (Envelope mA)
  - Le Comité de Secours et d’Alimentation de la Province de Liège, 22 February 1915 (Envelope mA)
  - "Élèves de l’école moyenne professionnelle de demoiselles de la ville de Liège," August 1916 (Envelope mB)
  - CRB group photograph, undated (Map case)
  - Comité de Secours et d’Alimentation de la Province de Liège, 22 February 1915 (Map case)
  - CRB members portrait album, 1917 (Box 1)
- Printed materials, 1917-1919
  Contains lithographs, scrapbook, and printed matter relating to the Comité de Secours et d'Alimentation de l’Arrondissement de Liège activities. The scrapbook includes news-clippings relating to Chatfield's CRB work and the United States' lending pledge to the CRB. Arranged by format.
  - "Oeuvre des Diners Economique," poster, undated (Box 2)
  - Lithograph, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Le Comité National de Secours et d’Alimentation, lithograph, with identity chart, 1914-1918 (Map case)
  - The History of the CRB, by Tracy Kittredge, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Rapport de la Commission du Lait, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Scraps of Paper: German Proclamations in Belgium and France, undated (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1917 (Box 2)
- Memorabilia, circa 1914-1917
  Contains decorated flour sacks relating to CRB flour distribution in Belgium and a framed certificate.
  - Flour sacks. 1 embroidered design and 2 painted designs (Box 2)
  - Certificate, undated (Art racks)